rafflecopter.com 2013-12-16

# Rafflecopter - Privacy Policy :)

Privacy comes first and foremost at Rafflecopter. Your privacy is critically important to us. This privacy policy is effective 10/15/2012; it summarizes what information we might collect from a registered user or other visitor, and what we will and will not do with it. 

First, we have a few fundamental principles at Rafflecopter: 

  * We don’t ask you for personal information unless we truly need it to provide our services.
  * We don’t share your personal information with anyone except to comply with the law, develop our products, or protect our rights.
  * We don’t sell personal information. Your name and email address will never be given or sold to a 3rd party.
  * We don’t store personal information on our servers unless it’s required for the on-going operation of one of our services.

##  WEBSITE VISITORS 

Like most website operators, Rafflecopter collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. Rafflecopter’s purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how Rafflecopter’s visitors use its website. 

From time to time, Rafflecopter may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its website. For example, here’s a blog post we wrote a blog post describing the number of entry options Rafflecopter users typically use: 

<http://blog.rafflecopter.com/2012/06/giveaway-entry-options/>

If you read the paragraphs following the title ‘Survey Results Aside: The Hard Data’, this is a perfect example of how we’ve used non-personally-identifying information in an aggregate. 

Rafflecopter also collects potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses for logged in users and for users leaving comments on Rafflecopter blogs. Rafflecopter only discloses logged in user and commenter IP addresses under the same circumstances that it uses and discloses personally-identifying information as described below, except that blog commenter IP addresses are visible and disclosed to the administrators of the blog where the comment was left. 

One other exception is when a Rafflecopter giveaway is entered by a logged in user, the IP address of the entrant will be logged and available for the giveaway administrator to view with the intentions of using this information to help moderate giveaway entries. It’s common for sweepstakes promotions run by giveaway administrators to limit entries into their giveaways to one per household or per IP address, as an IP address might represent an individual household. 

##  GATHERING OF PERSONALLY-IDENTIFYING INFORMATION 

Certain visitors to Rafflecopter’s websites choose to interact with Rafflecopter in ways that require Rafflecopter to gather personally-identifying information. The amount and type of information that Rafflecopter gathers depends on the nature of the interaction. For example, we ask visitors who sign up for an account at Rafflecopter to provide a name and email address. Those who engage in transactions with Rafflecopter – by purchasing access to a premium service for example – are asked to provide additional information, including as necessary the personal and financial information required to process those transactions. 

In each case, Rafflecopter collects such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the visitor’s interaction with Rafflecopter. Rafflecopter does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. And visitors can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities. 

##  RAFFLECOPTER GIVEAWAY WIDGET ENTRANTS 

When an individual enters a Rafflecopter giveaway, they’re able to log into the widget in two ways - through Facebook Connect and through their name and email address combination. 

Facebook Connect for Entrants 

Many of our users prefer using their Facebook account to connect to our giveaway widgets across the web. When an entrant signs in through Facebook Connect, they will be shown a dialog hosted by Facebook that describes Rafflecopter giveaway app’s permissions. This dialog comes in a pop-up form that looks like this: 

We currently ask for only basic information and email address. By default, your basic information is the information you’ve chosen to make public that’s associated with your Facebook account. This includes certain properties such as your Facebook id, name, picture, gender, and your locale. Certain connections such as your friends also may be available. If the user has made more of their data public, more information will be available. 

We ask for your email address associated with your Facebook account as an entrant if you win a giveaway, the promotion admin may be able to contact you. If you enter a giveaway using Rafflecopter’s widget and log into the widget through Facebook Connect, you will be contacted if you’re a winner at the primary email address listed in your Facebook account. This email address can be found and edited by logging into your Facebook account > general account settings > email. 

  * We take your privacy seriously and stand by the following guidelines when it comes to your Facebook account:
  * We will never post anything to your wall unless you give us permission.
  * We will never contact your Facebook friends without your approval.
  * We will never store your Facebook password.
  * We will only use information you have made publicly available to the Facebook community.
  * We encourage you to take control of how and what you share on Facebook by editing and reading more about your privacy settings on Facebook here: <http://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/>

To disconnect the Rafflecopter application from your Facebook account, log into your Facebook account, go to your Facebook account settings, click on ‘apps’ on the left side of the screen, find the Rafflecopter app and click the x in the row to remove the app. 

##  Name / Email Address for Entrants 

If you choose not to log into a Rafflecopter giveaway widget via Facebook Connect, the other option is to use your name and email address. This contact information is needed to give to the administrator of the giveaway to help them determine if you’re a winner and contact you if you win. 

When an entrant signs into and enters a Rafflecopter giveaway, their entrant information is collected by Rafflecopter and presented to the giveaway administrator to make the job of the giveaway administrator easy to run, manage, and moderate their giveaways and giveaway entrants. 

Here’s a screenshot of an example spreadsheet that a giveaway administrator will have access to during and after the giveaway: 

In the example, Bob Smith, the giveaway entrant, entered the giveaway with his name and email address. You can also see that Bob Smith entered the giveaway three times. The admin of the giveaway has access to Bob’s name, email address, the extra info that Bob entered into the giveaway widget, when he entered, as well as IP. This ‘list’ of entrants that the giveaway admin has access to helps them moderate and verify entries into their giveaway. 

As stated above, Rafflecopter presents this data to the administrator running the giveaway. We also give the administrator the ability to download a list of entries into a spreadsheet format. 

If you’re entering a Rafflecopter giveaway on a 3rd party site, please be sure that you read the giveaway entrant’s privacy policy and feel comfortable giving this entrant information to the party running the promotion. If you have reason to believe the giveaway administrator is using this list maliciously, please contact us at privacy@rafflecopter.com. 

##  AGGREGATED STATISTICS 

Rafflecopter may collect statistics about the behavior of visitors to its websites. For instance, Rafflecopter may monitor the most frequented giveaways on the Rafflecopter site. Rafflecopter also has Google Analytics installed on our site as well as other analytic programs that help us gather feedback and make decisions on how to improve our service offerings. However, Rafflecopter does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. 

##  PROTECTION OF CERTAIN PERSONALLY-IDENTIFYING INFORMATION 

Rafflecopter discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those of its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it on Rafflecopter’s behalf or to provide services available at Rafflecopter’s websites, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others. Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; by using Rafflecopter’s websites, you consent to the transfer of such information to them. 

As an example, if you’re having trouble with choosing a winner (whether that be user error or a bug on our end) and you file a support ticket, an employee of Rafflecopter may access your account to help decide how to best remedy the solution. This might include opening up your list of entries and seeing entrant information. 

Rafflecopter will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone. Other than to its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations, as described above, Rafflecopter discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only in response to a subpoena, court order or other governmental request, or when Rafflecopter believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of Rafflecopter, third parties or the public at large. 

If you are a registered user of an Rafflecopter website and have supplied your email address, Rafflecopter may occasionally send you an email to tell you about new features, solicit your feedback, or just keep you up to date with what’s going on with Rafflecopter and our products. We primarily use our blog, Facebook page, and Twitter account to communicate this type of information, so we expect to keep this type of email to a minimum. If you send us a request (for example via a support email or via one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish it in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users. Rafflecopter takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information. 

##  COOKIES 

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. Rafflecopter uses cookies to help Rafflecopter identify and track visitors, their usage of Rafflecopter website, and their website access preferences. Rafflecopter visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using Rafflecopter’s websites, with the drawback that certain features of Rafflecopter’s websites may not function properly without the aid of cookies. 

##  EXTERNAL DATA STORAGE SITES 

We may store your data on servers provided by third party hosting vendors with whom we have contracted. 

##  NOTICE TO EUROPEAN UNION USERS 

Rafflecopter’s operations of business are located primarily in the United States. If you provide information to us, the information will be transferred out of the European Union (EU) to the United States. By providing personal information to us, you are consenting to its storage and use as described herein. 

##  INFORMATION COLLECTED FROM CHILDREN 

You must be at least 13 years old to use Rafflecopter‘s web site(s) & service(s). Rafflecopter does not knowingly collect information from children under 13. See the U.S. Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act here: 

<http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Children%27s_Online_Privacy_Protection_Act>

If you are under the age of 13, please do not submit any personal data through the site. We encourage parents and legal guardians to monitor their children’s internet usage and to help enforce our privacy policy by instructing their children never to provide personal data through Rafflecopter without their permission. 

##  BUSINESS TRANSFERS 

If Rafflecopter, or substantially all of its assets were acquired, or in the unlikely event that Rafflecopter goes out of business or enters bankruptcy, user information would be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that any acquiror of Rafflecopter may continue to use your personal information as set forth in this policy. 

##  ADS 

Ads appearing on any of our websites may be delivered to users by advertising partners, who may set cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement to compile information about you or others who use your computer. This information allows ad networks to, among other things, deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. This Privacy Policy covers the use of cookies by Rafflecopter and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers. 

##  YOUR PRIVACY RESPONSIBILITIES 

To help protect your privacy on Rafflecopter, be sure: 

  * Not to share your user ID or password with anyone 
  * To log off the Rafflecopter web site when you are finished
  * To take customary precautions to guard against ‘malware’

##  PRIVACY POLICY CHANGES 

Although most changes are likely to be minor, Rafflecopter may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in Rafflecopter’s sole discretion. Rafflecopter encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. If you have a Rafflecopter account, you should also check your dashboard for alerts to these changes. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change. 

##  QUESTIONS OR COMMENTS? 

We love our users and take their privacy very seriously. If you have any questions or comments about Rafflecopter‘s privacy policy, please send a message to privacy@rafflecopter.com. 

Effective October 15th 2012 

## Blogger

$7.99/month

| 

## Business

$59.99/month  
  
---|---  
  
  * Add prize photos!
  * Change start/end times!
  * Unlimited CSV downloads
  * E-Z Terms/Conditions
  * Email reminders
  * More entry options 
    * +PINTEREST AND SURVEYS
  * Mobile-friendly FB app
  * Rafflecopter branding
  * Real-time analytics
  * Email list integration 
    * +MAILCHIMP, AWEBER, CONSTANT CONTACT
  * Viral refer-a-friend entries

| 

  * Add prize photos!
  * Change start/end times!
  * Unlimited CSV downloads
  * E-Z Terms/Conditions
  * Email reminders
  * More entry options 
    * +PINTEREST AND SURVEYS
  * Mobile-friendly FB app
  * No Rafflecopter branding
  * Real-time analytics
  * Email list integration 
    * +MAILCHIMP, AWEBER, CONSTANT CONTACT
  * Viral refer-a-friend entries

Upgrade to blogger

_easy to cancel at any time_ | 

Upgrade to business

_easy to cancel at any time_
